chelseasmessyapron.com 2019-12-30

# Disclosure & Privacy Policy | Chelsea's Messy Apron

Chelsea’s Messy Apron is committed to maintaining the privacy and protection of your personal information. This privacy policy tells you about the information we collect on our website located at www.chelseasmessyapron.com (“Site”) and how we use that information. By using the Site, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this privacy policy, which may be modified from time to time by us.

While using our Site, we may gather certain information from you. The information we gather falls into two categories: (1) information you supply, and (2) information collected as you navigate through our Site.

### Information You Supply

Chelsea’s Messy Apron may collect certain information directly from you. This could include website registration, comment forms, online surveys, and other online forms that ask users to provide their names, e-mail addresses, and other contact information. This information is used solely by Chelsea’s Messy Apron and is never sold to third parties.

### Information Collected Through Navigation

**Cookies** : Cookies are files containing a small amount of data related to your visit on our site. Cookies are sent to your browser from our Site and stored on your computer’s hard drive. You can choose to disable cookies by changing the settings on your browser. However, if you choose to disable this function, you may not be able to use some portions of our Site.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;

(b) status – we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website;

(c) personalization – we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you;

(d) security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally;

(e) advertising – we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you; and

(f) analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services;

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Amazon Services LLC Associates Program is an affiliate advertising program whereby the Site uses cookies to track visits to allow the Site to earn commissions. Amazon will track referrals to the site through the use of cookies. Please see [Amazon](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496)‘s privacy policy for more information.

**Log Files** : Like many other websites, Chelsea’s Messy Apron makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Device Addresses** : Each user’s computer IP address, device MAC address, or similar address (“device address”) is logged with each visit and each action performed on the Site. This information is never provided to third parties, except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, and is logged only for a temporary period of time. Device address information is linked to personal information and may be used in an effort to block a “banned” user from accessing the Site.

**Advertising; Third Party Cookies** : We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Site. These third parties include business partners and advertising networks, which collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of their advertisements or with a social sharing button displayed on our Site. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your interest or preferences so that they can display advertisements or promotional material on this Site and on other sites across the Internet tailored to your apparent interests.

We do not have access to, or control over, the technologies that these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

For more information about this practice and to understand whether and how you may prevent the use of interest based advertising and your opt-out choices, please click here: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this Site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads based on your visit to this Site and other websites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

### Children Under 13

We care about protecting the privacy of children. We won’t knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide us any personally identifying information. Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any information about themselves (such as their names, email addresses, and phone numbers) over the Internet, to us or to anyone else. If you’re under 13, please do not provide us with any personally identifying information (such as your name, your email address or your phone number).

### California Privacy Rights

California law requires that operators of websites and online services disclose how they respond to a Do Not Track signal and whether other third parties may collect personal information about an individual’s online activities from their website or service. Some browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the website or online service that a user visits, indicating that the user does not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret Do Not Track signals, we do not currently respond to Do Not Track signals. We continue to work with the online industry to define a common understanding of how to treat Do Not Track signals.

### Third Party Websites

Chelsea’s Messy Apron may include links to external, or third party websites. Chelsea’s Messy Apron’s privacy policy does not apply to these third party websites, and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those other websites

### Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we make no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, misuse, to you or to any third party arising out of any such loss, misuse, or alteration.

### Comments

Chelsea’s Messy Apron may include interactive forms such as comments. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. Such information may be read, collected, or used by other users of this Site, including anonymous visitors. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

### Visiting our Site from outside the United States

If you are visiting our Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States, where our servers are located. By using our Site, you agree that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it, as described in this Privacy Policy.

### Additional Information for European Visitors

If you use or interact with our Site then the data controller will be Chelsea’s Messy Apron, LLC.

We process your information to meet our legitimate interests when we use your information to provide you with our content, products and/or services, to communicate with you, for our advertising and marketing purposes and in the context of a corporate transaction. To accomplish our legitimate interests, we may share your information with our corporate affiliates, service providers and business partners (including for our advertising and marketing purposes) and in the context of a corporate transaction.

### Updates and Changes

We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time. You should check this page periodically to ensure that you are aware of the current policy. Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of Chelsea’s Messy Apron then you may contact us by clicking [here](https://www.chelseasmessyapron.com/contact/).

Chelsea’s Messy Apron receives compensation from third parties in exchange for advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of promotions. The compensation received will not influence the content or opinions found on this Site. All advertising is in the form of advertisements generated by a third party ad network. Those advertisements will be identified as paid advertisements.

Please note that Chelsea’s Messy Apron has financial relationships with some of the merchants mentioned here. Chelsea’s Messy Apron may be compensated if consumers choose to utilize the links located throughout the content on this site and generate sales for the said merchant.

From time to time, the owner of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner of this blog may receive compensation for certain posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are authentic. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

### Amazon Services LLC Associates Program 

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

### Nutrition Information Disclosure

The writers and publishers of Chelsea’s Messy Apron are not nutritionists or registered dietitians. This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

This Site may offer estimated nutritional information for recipes contained on the Site, such as calories, fat, carbs, etc. This information is provided as a courtesy and is not guaranteed to be accurate.

Last updated: February 6, 2019
